Katherine Gil

Software Engineer



(210) 560 4454



gil.katherine22@gmail.com



Linkedin/katherinegil22



GitHub/katygil7

United States Army veteran with 5+ years of relevant leadership experience and exceptional problem-solving skills in fast-paced environments. Experiencing a career change to Software Engineering. Ability to produce quality software solutions and co-create emerging technologies to optimize system support while maintaining existing software functionality. Eager to collaborate and contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, and strong communication skills. Excited for professional growth and career development in the latest innovative technologies to accelerate business impact.

Technical Skills

HTML - CSS - Bootstrap - JavaScript - jQuery - Java SE - Java EE (Servlets, JSP) - Spring - MySQL - React - Object-Oriented Programming - Test-Driven Development - Version Control with GitHub - Visual Studio Code - IntelliJ - Paired Programming

Exposed to: Python

Development Projects

My Portfolio

- Built a website to showcase all projects, personal information, and capabilities to make a resume more interactive; resulting in a 50% increase in skills credibility.
- Incorporated features; downloadable resume, social media hyperlinks, and static navbar.
- Environment: React, CSS on the front-end.
- Tools: Visual Studio Code (VS Code), React tools, GitHub Pages, GitHub repositories and EmailJS.

i-Plant

- Designed and created dynamic Ecommerce website with products for sale by 5 developers utilizing scrum and agile programming methods; leading to a 100% completion on time of all sprint's and the product development.
- Incorporated features; capability to gather a plant's basic information based on an uploaded image with be 90% accurate utilizing the API call. Ability to add to a shopping cart, and to make payments.
- Environment: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, and MySQL technology languages.
- Tools: IntelliJ, Github repositories, Stripe and PlantNet API's, Adminer, Trello, Postman, and Google Auth.

Weather Map

- Developed a site that displays 99% real-time five day forecast reports based on desired input location with a dynamic geographic world map visibility.
- Environment: Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Tools: IntelliJ, Github repositories, Mapbox and Openweather API's.

GreenCup Films

- Paired-programing single-page application displaying movies from a JSON file in Glitch with CRUD capabilities.
- Incorporated feature; 100% team database creation.
- Environment: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Tools: IntelliJ, Github repositories.

Coffee

- Paired-programming project with CRUD user interface capability to look for desirable coffee roasts.
- Incorporated feature: 100% team database creation.
- Environment: Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Tools: IntelliJ, Github repositories and Bootstrap.

Professional Experience

San Antonio - San Antonio, TX

Real Estate Agent / eXp / Aug 2021 - Oct 2022

- Negotiated over \$700,000 on sales by actively communicating with third-party professionals resulting in successfully closed transactions and an average of 80% of the year's goal.
- Developed a network of 20+ mortgage lenders, inspectors, contractors that provided services to clients leading to 90% customer satisfaction.
- Prepared approx. 100 legal documents to include contracts, purchase agreements, and leases resulting in 75% acceptance rate during the year 2021.
- Led and taught a team of 3 to use the appropriate technologies and strategies to buy distressed properties at a 25% price reduction.
- Able to pick up new technologies quickly.

Fort Bragg - Fayetteville, NC

Project Manager / U.S Army / Apr 2015 - Oct 2020

- Performed 1,000+ water quality analysis and advanced water tests to ensure potable water for all members during training exercises that resulted in a 100% readiness rate.
- Supervised a 15-person team providing individual mentorship to encourage leadership and professional development leading to an 80% promotion rate.
- Distributed over 7 million gallons of fuel in support of Operation Inherent Resolve Iraq 2017; resulting in a 100% supply readiness rate.
- Planned a method to receive and test fuel from Iraqi contractors that optimized delivery quantity; resulting in a weekly delivery rate increase of 50%.
- Achieved 100% average delivery rate on supplies leading to \$0 non-expandable losses.
- Managed inventory for equipment's operational readiness by scheduling regular maintenance of 15 armor vehicles valued at more than \$5.4 million; resulting in decreased order costs by 20%.

Education

Codeup

Certification of Completion

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 20-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development.

William Peace University

Bachelor of Sport and Fitness Studies.

GPA: 3.7

Additional Information

Bilingual - Spanish